In this video, we'll be going over the installation of the Go tool chain and Visual Studio Code.
The first thing you'll do is open up a web browser and navigate to go.dev.
Once the page loads, click on the download link.
Under feature downloads, if you're on Windows, click on the link for Microsoft Windows,
then click on save file.
Save it wherever you like.
Once the download completes, open up the installer.
Click on next, click the checkbox and click next.
I'm using defaults, so I just click next all the way through and then click install.
Once the install completes, click finish.
After clicking finish, your Go tool chain is ready to run.
Next, we'll be installing Visual Studio Code in its extensions.
Back in your web browser, navigate to code.visualstudio.com
Click on the download for Windows link.
Wait for a moment and then click on save file. Save it wherever you like.
Once the download completes, open it up.
You'll need to accept the agreement and click next.
I use defaults for everything, so I just click next all the way through and then click on install.
Once the installation is complete, make sure the launch Visual Studio Code button is checked and click on finish.
And it may take a moment to launch the first time.
Once Visual Studio Code loads, we're going to click on the extensions button on the left.
We'll type in Go, and it should be the first results in our extensions and have several million downloads.
We'll then click on the install button.
After you click on the install button, we'll need to open up a Go file in order to finish the installation.
To do so, we can go back to the getting started page and click on open folder and open up the course content materials that you've downloaded.
I saved mine into my documents, so just navigate to it and click select folder and then open up any of the Go files.
You'll have a pop-up that says install or install all. Just click on install all.
This installation process may take a lot of time as there are a lot of tools to download and install in order to get Visual Studio Code set up for Go programming.
Once your installation finishes, click on always update if you get a pop-up.
And you should see in your terminal that the tools have been successfully installed and you'll have a message that indicates you're ready to go.
Once you see that message, then everything is good to go and we can start the course.